Gabriel Lima

gcamilo@kaist.ac.kr·+82-10-7278-7236 https://thegcamilo.github.io/·https://medium.com/@thegcamilo 291 Daehak-ro, KAIST, Yuseong-gu, Daejeon, South Korea, 34141

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My previous research focus was on emotional content in speech, audio and text. Right now, I intend to work on computational social science, data mining, statistical inference and machine learning. I would like to apply these methods to political trends and behavior analysis in social media and crowdsourcing experiments.

EDUCATION

B.S. in Computer Science - KAIST, South Korea

Feb. 2017 - present

Machine Learning · Social Computing · Computer Vision

Computer Science Technical High School - COTIL, UNICAMP, Brazil

Feb. 2013 - Dec. 2015

Software Engineering · Database · Data Structures

PUBLICATIONS

Gabriel Lima and JinYeong Bak. "Speech Emotion Classification using Raw Audio Input and Transcriptions". Proceedings of the 2018 International Conference on Signal Processing and Machine Learning. ACM, 2018.

WORK EXPERIENCES

Research Intern - KAIST Data Science Lab, South Korea

Jan. 2019 - present

Study of political speech in Twitter · Social media data visualization

Teaching Assistant - English as First Language Department, KAIST

Aug. 2018 - Dec. 2018

Administration work · Paper and homework grading

BLOG POSTS AND PAPERS

How Presidential Candidates and Parties Tweeted During the 2018 Brazilian Election. PDF available on my website.

A Quick Analysis of Movie Duration Based on Its Genre and Rating. Available on Medium.

My Spotify Playlists' Sentiment, Track Popularity and Genre Analysis. Available on Medium.

Honors and Awards

Best Presentation Award Received at the 2018 International Conference on Signal Processing and Machine Learning (SPML 2018), Shanghai, China.

School of Computing Dean's List Received for high academic achievement, Fall Semester 2018, KAIST.

PROGRAMMING SKILLS

Proficient Python · NumPy · Matplotlib · PyTorch · scikit-learn Knowledgeable pandas · Tensorflow · XGBoost · MATLAB · C

LANGUAGES

Portuguese (mother tongue) · English (fluent) · Spanish (intermediate) · Korean (beginner)